Don't look so uneasy, Number Two.
そう不安そうな顔をするものでもなかろうよ 二人目
I'm a specialist.
拙者は専門家でござる
Times have changed, but I won't ignore the mark of someone else in my trade.
時代は違えど戦士として
同業の落款印を無視したりはせぬよ
"This is my prey, so hands off."
"これは我が獲物だから手を出すな"
That's what the mark on your face means.
という意味合いの
言うなら専門家同士の目印じゃ
I won't attack you while you bear it.
それがあるうちは
おぬしは拙者にとって不可侵の存在じゃわ
If it wasn't there...
その印がなければ...
I would never let a vampire live.
拙者が吸血鬼なんて
一瞬だって生かしておくものか
I'm glad a little girl stepped on my face after all.
ここがよかろう
This looks good.
ここならゆっくり話せそうじゃ
Here we can talk in peace.
阿良々木暦 と申したか
Araragi Koyomi... That was your name, I believe?
阿良々木殿と呼ばせてもらおうかの
Let me call you Sir Araragi, if you please.
I won't beat around the bush, Sir Araragi.
単刀直入に申しあげるぞ 阿良々木殿
Break up with Kiss-Shot.
キスショットと別れて欲しい
End Story
Shinobu Mail
Shinobu Mail Part Five
End Story
My goal is
拙者の目的は
making up with Kiss-Shot, known as Oshino Shinobu to you.
キスショット おぬしが言うところの忍野忍との
仲直りにてござる
M-Making...
な... なか?
Up.
直り
We broke up after an argument.
拙者はキスショットと喧嘩別れしておる
I said some things I didn't mean and hurt her.
一時的な気の迷いで
キスショットに心無い言葉を投げかけた
I want to apologize and hope she'll forgive me.
そのことを謝って 許してもらいたい
そしてかつてのように 共に怪異と戦いたい
And then... I want to combat oddities with her again.
Her divine beauty sends shivers down my spine.
女神のように美しい
背筋が凍るほど美しいあれの背を守り
刀となって戦いたい
I want to be the blade that protects her.
おぬしにはわからないだろうが
You probably have no eye for it.
そう言ってうまいこと忍に近付いて
復讐するつもりだとしか思えない
Say what you want, but my impression is that you want to get close to her to enact your revenge.
復讐? 復讐とは何の復讐かのう?
Revenge? For what?
拙者にあれを恨む理由があるとでも言うのかのう?
Do I have a reason to resent her?
恨む理由は...
A reason?
Yes.
ある
Telling me you didn't mean what you said is a lie.
一時的な気の迷いなんて言葉で誤魔化すなよ
お前は忍に 酷い言葉を投げかけた
What you said to her was very cruel.
Yes, I don't deny that.
ああ それ自体は否定せぬ
だから謝りたいのだ
That's why I want to apologize.
直接会って 謝りたい
I want to apologize directly.
She only needs one kin.
彼女の眷属は一人でいい
She revived me when I was on the brink of death.
瀕死(ひんし)だった拙者を生き返らせてくれたのだ
当時はおこだったが
今となっては感謝しておる
It made me very salty at the time, but now I'm grateful to her.
拙者の言っていることはそんなにおかしいかのう?
Does what I say sound that strange to you?
おこと言っているのはおかしいと思うが
Using the word "salty" is what's strange to me,
しかし その発言自体を否定することは
僕ではできない
but I can't refute what you're saying
まったく同じことをしているようなものなのだから
because I feel the exact same way.
別れたくないのかのう
Are you reluctant to break up?
だが おぬしの代わりは誰にでもできるが
拙者の代わりは誰にもできぬよ
Anybody could replace you, but nobody can replace me.
なぜなら 拙者は特別だから
I am special, you see.
選ばれた人間だから
I'm the chosen human.
憧れるね そういう台詞
I love lines like that.
一度でいいから言ってみたいぜ
I wish I had a chance to say them.
Sadly, they're too presumptuous for me.
烏滸(おこ)がましくてとても言えないけれど
身供(みども)が火花を散らしても
誰の得にもならない
Nothing is gained by discord between us.
結局こんなもの 一人の女を二人の男が
取り合っているようなものなのだからのう
In the end, we are basically two men fighting over one woman.
Oddities wouldn't meddle in a fight between their slaves.
奴隷同士の喧嘩など 怪異も喰うまい
じゃあ どうするんだよ
What's going to happen now?
ここからは互いに褒め合うのか?
Will we be showering each other with praise?
That would be quite unsightly.
それこそ目も当てられまい
だから拙者はメリットを提示しよう
I'll show you the merits.
阿良々木殿 おぬしがキスショットと別れてくれたら
おぬしにどんないいことがあるかを教えてしんぜよう
Let me explain the positive outcomes once you break up with her.
その間におぬしは おぬしがキスショットと別れなければ
拙者にどんないいことがあるのかを考えてくれればよい
While I do that, try to think of the good things that can happen if you don't break up.
め メリット? いいこと?
The merits? The positives?
もしもキスショットと別れてくれたなら
おぬしはキスショットから解放される
You would be released from Kiss-Shot if you break up.
Think of it as me shouldering the responsibility that has, until now, been borne by you.
つまり おぬしが現在 キスショットに対して負っている責任を
拙者が肩代わりしてやろうということに他ならぬ
お前からのメッセージは ちゃんと伝えたよ
I gave her your message.
I don't think she wants to
お前に会うつもりは
ないみたいだぜ
see you.
I see.
そうか
まあ そうであろうな
I'm not that surprised.
だがまあ キスショットがたとえどういうつもりであろうとも
貸しているものは返してもらわないと な
But whatever her feelings,
I must have back what I gave away.
刀を...
My sword...
そして立場を
And my position.
返り咲きたいのでござる
I want to try again.
拙者は 四百年を経て もう一度輝きたいのでござる
I want to shine again, after four hundred years.
I see nothing wrong with that.
それがみっともないとは思わぬ
Try what again? Being human, not her kin, right?
返り咲きたいのは 忍の眷属じゃあなくて
人間にじゃあないのか?
忍に会いたいというのは 復讐が目的じゃなかったとしても
人間に戻りたいからってことも
Even if your goal wasn't enacting revenge on her,
perhaps you want to be human ag—
I can't go back to being human.
拙者はもう人間には戻れぬ
なにせ四百年じゃ
It's been four hundred years.
時間が経ち過ぎた
Too much time has passed.
そういう視点から見ても 拙者はおぬしとは違う
I am different from you in that respect.
You know, I'm past lamenting that.
まあ... それを悲しいとは もう思わぬよ
間に合わないからこそ 拙者はこれからずっと 半永久的に
キスショットと共にいられるのだから
It's too late now, and that's precisely why I can spend eternity semi-permanently with her.
Maybe you think of that kind of love as pure,
それを純愛だって思っているのかもしれないけれど
お前みたいなのを 現代社会じゃ
ストーカーって言ってるぜ
but nowadays that'd make you a stalker.
悪口の言い合いは だからやめようではないか
Look, let's not turn this into a dung-flinging contest.
それよりも 何か思いついたかの?
Have you thought of something?
おぬしがキスショットと別れないことによって
拙者には全体どんないいことがあるのかのう?
What good could possibly come to you if you stay together with Kiss-Shot?
Don't just drink what's given to you by the enemy.
敵から出された飲み物を
疑問なく飲もうとしてんじゃねえよ
聖水なんか飲まされたら たとえペアリングが切れてる今のお前でも
ひとたまりもねーぜ
Your link might be broken,
but if that's holy water, you'd be done for.
Friggin' hilarious.
超ウケる
邪魔が入ったようでござるな 阿良々木殿
Seems that we've been interrupted, Sir Araragi.
毒杯ならぬ聖杯を ここでおぬしが呷(あお)ってくれていたら
話は早かったのじゃがの
We could have skipped a few pages if you had drunk my wholly, and holy, unpoisoned chalice.
おぬしが自らの意志で勝手に浄化される分には
落款印を無視したことにもならぬしの
If you so choose to cleanse yourself, why,
that can hardly be called ignoring the mark.
Don't be mad, kin of Heart-Under-Blade.
怒るなよ ハートアンダーブレードの眷属
怪異退治の方法なんて なんでもありなんだ
There are many ways to exorcise oddities.
騙し討ちも不意打ちも 立派な作法のひとつだぜ
Deceit and treachery are just as respectable as any other.
Looks like we made it.
どうやら間に合ったようだね
よかったよかった
How nice.
初めまして 初代くん
Nice to meet you, First One.
My name is Gaen Izuko.
私は臥煙伊豆湖
何でも知ってるおねーさんだ
I know everything.
きみと交渉しに来た
I've come to negotiate with you.
阿良々木殿 どうやら話し合いはこれまでのようじゃ
Sir Araragi, I believe our conversation is at an end.
I must excuse myself.
これにて御免
拙者とおぬしでは
妥協点を見つけられなかった
We couldn't find common ground.
こうなると 拙者達の関係は
次なる段階に移行せざるを得ぬ
I'm afraid I must take our relationship to the next level.
Conversation?
話し合いって
決闘でござる
We duel.
今夜 殺し合おう
Tonight, we fight to the death.
I leave the details to the specialist squad over there.
細かい段取りはそちらの専門家陣に任せるわ
それまでに 拙者は拙者の状態を
できる限り全快にしておくでござる
I will hopefully recover all my abilities before then.
阿良々木殿は
その顔の落款印を外しておくがよかろう
Please work on removing that mark, Sir Araragi.
拙者は逃げも隠れもせぬ
I will neither run nor hide.
Why aren't Episode and Gaen going after him?
H
o
u
s
e
w
i
f
e
P
h
o
t
S
u
d
i
o
ち—
D—
Don't get the wrong idea!
違うんだ!
Bra
Donuts
Book
Bra
Donuts
Book
Bra
Donuts
Book
Bra
Donuts
Book
Bra
Donuts
Book
Bra
Donuts
Book
Bra
Donuts
Book
Bra
Donuts
Book
Bra
Donuts
Book
Bra
Donuts
Book
Bra
Donuts
Book
Bra
Donuts
Book
Bra
Donuts
Book
Bra
Donuts
Book
Bra
Donuts
Book
Bra
Donuts
Book
Bra
Donuts
Book
Bra
Donuts
Book
Bra
Donuts
Book
Bra
Donuts
Book
Bra
Donuts
Book
Bra
Donuts
Book
Bra
Donuts
Book
Bra
Donuts
Book
Bra
Donuts
Book
Bra
Donuts
Book
Bra
Donuts
Book
Bra
Donuts
Book
Bra
Donuts
Book
Bra
Donuts
Book
Bra
Donuts
Book
Bra
Donuts
Book
Bra
Donuts
Book
Bra
Donuts
Book
Bra
Donuts
Book
Bra
Donuts
Book
Bra
Donuts
Book
Bra
Donuts
Book
Bra
Donuts
Book
Bra
Donuts
Book
Bra
Donuts
Book
Bra
Donuts
Book
Bra
Donuts
Book
Bra
Donuts
Book
Bra
Donuts
Book
Bra
Donuts
Book
Bra
Donuts
Book
Bra
Donuts
Book
Bra
Donuts
Book
Bra
Donuts
Book
鬼いちゃん しい
Be quiet.
お 斧乃木ちゃん
Ononoki?
僕が来たときにはもうああなっていた
They've been like that since I arrived.
ああなってたって...
Like what?
おい
Well,
you've got guts. I'll grant you that.
うぬの度胸は認めてやる
この儂を相手に一歩も退かんその蛮勇(ばんゆう)は
なるほど我があるじ様の後輩といった感じじゃわい
You take after your elder in your foolhardy refusal to back away from me.
じゃから ここは感情的にならず 五百年生きた大人として
ガキに寛容になってやる
I won't get angry now. I'll be a mature, forbearing, five hundred year old adult.
If you take back what you said earlier, I will forget this little incident.
さっきの発言を取り消すと言うのならば
ここでのやり取りはなかったことにしてやってもよい
謝れば
Apologize,
許してやる
and I will forgive you.
I won't take it back.
取り消さない
謝らない
I won't apologize.
何度でも言う
I'll repeat what I said.
Shinobu, you have to meet him.
忍ちゃん きみは 会うべきだ
初代怪異殺しに会うべきだ
You have to meet the first oddity slayer.
四百年がかりで甦ったかつてのパートナーと
会わずに済まそうなんて
Cutting ties with some you worked with, reincarnated after four hundred years?
それは よくないことだ
That isn't good.
Not good at all.
とてもよくないことだ
It's not the right thing to do.
それは 正しくない
何を言っておるのか さっぱりわからんな
I have no idea what you're talking about.
If you want to lecture me,
at least provide some kind of logic.
人間の分際で儂に説教をしたいと言うのであれば
少しくらい論理立てて喋れ
Who cares about logic?
論理なんて知るか!
つべこべ言わず 会えばいいだろうが!
Stop whining and meet him!
He spent four hundred years regenerating just to meet you.
四百年がかりで
きみに会うためだけに復活した男だぞ
どうして会ってやらないんだ!
Why won't you meet him?!
I told you that you misunderstand.
じゃからそれはうぬの誤解じゃと言っておろうが
そんなくだらんエモーショナルな理由で
あやつは復活したわけではないわ
He didn't regenerate out of sentimental attachment.
The wind brought his scattered ashes together and they reached an excited state. It was a natural phenomenon.
散った灰が風で寄り集まって
磁石のように励起しただけの 自然現象じゃ
誰かが誰かを好きになる気持ちだって
自然だろうが!
And love is also a natural phenomenon!
誰かがきみを好きな気持ちを 否定するな!
Don't refuse someone's love!
Why do you just
だから...
わからん奴じゃなあ!
not understand?
That isn't how the relationship between
vampire and kin or master-servant works.
そういうのではないんじゃって
吸血鬼の眷属は 吸血鬼の主従関係は
It's not a matter of love or hate,
好き不好きで語るようなものじゃないんじゃ この
you silly fool.
恋愛脳が!
Your relationship has nothing to do with love or hate...
主従関係は 好き不好きではない
それをきみは
阿良々木先輩の前でも言えるのか
Would you say that with Araragi present?
あのとき 我があるじ様に言うた通りじゃ
Don't you remember what I told him earlier?
今の儂にとって
眷属と言える相手はうぬの先輩しかおらぬ
The only one I have to call kin right now is your friend.
Right now.
今の儂には
忍ちゃんは私の言っていることがわからないと言うけれど
私にわからないのは その辺だ
Maybe you don't understand what I say, but I don't understand that sentence.
私が気に入らないのは
まさしくその辺なのだ
I don't like it in the least.
It sounds like having more kin than one is a problem.
まるで眷属が一人しかいちゃあ
いけないみたいな言いかたじゃないか
たとえば忍ちゃんと 阿良々木先輩と その初代怪異殺しと
三人で仲良くやっていくという想定はないのか?
Is there no way for you three to all get along?
Three people...
三人でって
なんじゃ 仲直りをすればいいと
うぬは吐(ぬ)かすのか?
Are you saying we should make up?
I don't care if you make up.
仲直りをするかどうかはどうでもいい
もしも忍ちゃんが 初代怪異殺しよりも
阿良々木先輩を選ぶと言うのなら それでいいんだ
If you say you want to choose Araragi over the first oddity slayer, fine.
だけど それを相手に伝えるのは
忍ちゃんじゃなきゃならない
But you have to tell him that!
Don't leave it to Izuko or Araragi.
伊豆湖さんや阿良々木先輩に
任せるべきじゃあない
うぬは何もわかっておらん
You understand nothing.
儂とあやつとの関係性を
Not my relationship with him.
いや 今現在の
儂と我があるじ様の関係性さえ
Not even my relationship with my current master.
うぬは知らないのではないのか?
Do you dispute that?
確かに 知らない
No, I don't.
でも 私にはわかる
But I know more than you think.
初めての気持ちも
I know how it feels to be first
and yet still be in second place.
二番手の気持ちも
Kanbaru empathizes with the first oddity slayer more than any of us.
神原にとっては
初代怪異殺しの気持ちのほうがわかるのだ
With that persistent feeling so much like pure love.
純愛のごとき 偏執の気持ち
今更あやつに会ったところで
かけてやれる言葉なんぞないぞ
I have nothing to tell him even if we meet.
Accept reality, monkey girl.
現実を見ろ 猿娘
今やこの町に蔓延(まんえん)する
怪異譚そのものとさえ言えるあやつは
He is largely responsible for the
outbreak of oddities in this town,
専門家の餌食(えじき)になるしかない
and he will be hunted down by specialists.
わかってる
I know!
だから
That's why—
That's why? That's why I have to see him?
だから尚更(なおさら)会ってやるべき だと?
あの男は儂を恨んでおるんじゃぞ
He hates me.
会えば 儂は殺されるかもしれん
He might kill me.
妖刀を返せと言っておるらしいが
He wants his demon sword back.
その刀で斬られるのは
儂らだけでは済まんかもしれん
He might not be content with killing only me with it.
それも全部含めて
Take that into account, and—
You still have to see him!
それも全部含めて 会うべきだと言っている
だから理屈とかいいんだよ!
Nobody cares about logic!
なんでみんな そうやって人と会うことを拒むんだ
Why do people refuse to see others because of "logic"?
話にならない!
It solves nothing!
誰かと誰かが出会わなきゃ 話にならないだろうが!
Unless you meet in person, nothing improves!
You can't create a story unless you talk!
物語にならないだろうが
Just say it, Shinobu.
はっきり言えばいいだろう 忍ちゃん
怖いって
You're scared.
会うのが怖いって
Scared of seeing him.
会って話して 感情が乱れるのが嫌だって
You don't want to be emotionally swayed by what he could say.
You think meeting him would be akin to cheating on Araragi,
きみは 彼に会うことが
阿良々木先輩に対する裏切りのように思うから
彼と会わずにいるつもりかもしれないが
so maybe you want to get it over with without meeting him,
but that's a mistake.
それは違うぞ
きみが裏切っているのは 自分自身だ
The only one you're cheating is yourself.
言えばいいだろう
Just tell him.
四百年がかりで生き返ってくるような愛情は 重いって
Tell him that you can't be expected to hang onto his love for four hundred years!
Tell him that by reviving now,
he endangers what you've built with Araragi!
阿良々木先輩と仲良くやっているところに
今更生き返って来られても困るって
Tell him his love is a problem for you!
お前の気持ちは迷惑だって
Tell him he should have stayed in his grave!
そのまま死んでればよかったって
言えよ
Tell him.
それが言えないんだったら
主人だのあるじだの口にするな
If you can't do that, then don't
lecture me about lords and masters.
孤高でもなければ 高潔でもない
You're being neither aloof nor noble.
きみはただの人見知りだ
You're just bad with people.
何が主従関係だ
Master-servant relationship, my ass.
きみには 奴隷を持つ権利も
主人を持つ権利もない
You have the right to have neither slave nor master.
You don't have the right to build a relationship.
きみには 関係を築く権利がない
なぜ恋人つなぎ
Why the romantic hand-holding?
おっと 間違えたぜ 戦場ヶ原と
Sorry. Thought you were Senjougahara.
サイテー
You creep.
もうちょっとだけ待ってくれ 斧乃木ちゃん
Wait just a moment, Ononoki.
なんで
Why?
やばいよ もう
This is getting ugly.
Still.
それでもだ
遺言はそれでいいのか?
Will those be your last words?
すべてを台無しにしても
うぬの頭をこのまま潰してやりたい気分じゃわい
I really want to split your head open, even if it ruins everything.
やれよ だったら
Then do it.
私は謝らない
I won't apologize.
やって 今度は阿良々木先輩と気まずくなればいい
Do it and be on bad terms with Araragi.
きっと今 初代怪異殺しを避けているように
今度は阿良々木先輩を避けるんだろう
You'd just avoid him like you avoid the first oddity slayer.
今 彼を過去の話にしたように
Just like you consigned him to the past,
将来 阿良々木先輩のことも
昔話にすればいい
you'd consign Araragi to some ancient fairy tale.
きみは一人目を捨てるように
いつか二人目も捨てる
You'll throw away the second like you threw away the first.
一人目に向き合えないきみが
二人目に向き合えるわけがない
How would you face the second when you can't face the first?
三人目も 四人目も 五人目も
永遠に人と別れ続けろ
Number three, four, five—just keep breaking up forever!
Forever...
永遠に...
You're immortal, right?
不老不死なんだろう?
いつか言ってたよ 阿良々木先輩が
I'm sure Araragi told you
that if you died tomorrow he would go with you.
忍ちゃんが明日死ぬなら
僕の命は明日まででいいと
だけどきっと きみはそんなことは言わないな
But you wouldn't say that.
Even if you said it, you'd tell the third the same.
言ったとしても 同じことを
三人目にも言う
四人目にも言う
And the fourth.
五人目にも言う
And the fifth.
You'd repeat it over and over,
いつまでも言い続け
いつまでも生き続ける
and still survive.
誰もが己のように 社交的だと思うなよ?
Not everyone is as sociable as you.
さっき儂を人見知りとまとめてくれたが
You called me shy earlier.
誰かに会いたくないという気持ちだって
自然なものじゃろうが
Not wanting to see someone is a perfectly natural emotion.
It's not natural.
それは不自然だ
人と人は 合わないことはあっても
会わないことはない
Some people don't see eye to eye, but we have to see them anyway.
I'm not "people."
儂は人ではない
かもしれないな
Perhaps.
その様子だと
It certainly looks like it.
会ったところで 儂はあやつに
何を言ってやれるわけではないのじゃぞ?
I have nothing I could tell him when we'd meet.
憎み合って別れ
憎み合って死に別れた関係じゃ
Our union ended in spite, and spite was the only thing uniting us in death.
よりを戻すつもりもなければ
三人で仲良くやっていくつもりもない
I have no intention of patching things up,
or having the three of us get along together.
一人目と二人目を
並べて語るつもりもない
I have no intention of talking about them as equals.
比べること自体
我があるじ様に失礼じゃと思っておる
Merely comparing the two is a disservice to my current master.
What good is there in showing him my present harmony?
儂と我があるじ様が仲良くしておるところを見せ付けて
それで何の意味がある?
今やあの男に 儂が何の気持ちもないことを見せつけて
どんな意味がある?
What good is there in showing him no affection?
そんな残酷なことをしろというのか?
Are you saying I should be so pointlessly cruel?
ああ 残酷なことをしろと言っている
Yes, I'm saying you should be cruel.
昔の男を 傷つけるのがきみの仕事だ
It's your job to hurt your old partner.
きみは人に好かれて その上いい奴でいたいのか?
Do you want to be both a good person and loved by others?
愛されたままで終わりたいのか?
Do you want to languish in love?
うぬの言っておることは 風化や摩耗(まもう)させるくらいだったら
破壊してしまったほうがいいと言っておるようなものじゃぞ
You're basically saying things should be smashed before they fade.
Yes, I am, damn it!
言っているんだ だから
If he still hates me and tries to kill me,
I'd be forced to kill him.
あやつが儂を恨んで 殺そうとしておるのであれば
儂はあやつを殺し返すことになる
それでもいいのか?
Are you fine with that?
I am.
それでもいい
そのときは
憎しみという気持ちに応えてやればいい
Provide a relief for his hatred.
その思いを 断ち切ってやればいい
You can end the cycle.
だけど 謝って許してくれたなら
そのときは
But if he apologizes and you forgive him...
そのときだって同じことじゃ
The outcome is the same.
儂を許した直後に
あやつは専門家に退治される
Once I forgive him, he will be exorcised by the specialists.
それでもいいのか
Are you fine with that?
I am.
それでもいい
I am!
うぬの阿呆な予想通り
あの男が儂を想って復活したのだとしても
If you are right and he's come back to life out of love for me, I won't respond to his feelings.
儂がその想いに応えることはないぞ
儂があやつに会ってできることは
こっぴどく 手ひどく振るだけじゃ
All I can render unto him is cruelty.
それでもいいのか
Are you fine with that?
それでもいい
I am.
儂があやつに会って もしもその想いに応えたくなったら
どうする
What if I meet him and, hypothetically, want to respond to his feelings?
儂がうぬの先輩よりも 初代怪異殺しを選んだら
どうする
What if I choose the first oddity slayer over your friend?
それでもいいのか
Are you fine with that?
I am.
それでもいい
そのときは
そのときは 阿良々木先輩ときっぱり別れて
Break up with Araragi, properly,
彼と永遠に添い遂げるがいい
and be united in eternity with the other.
僕は 忍野忍が一対一で負けたのを初めて見た
That was the first time I saw Shinobu surrender one on one.
斧乃木ちゃん お願いがある
I want you to do something, Ononoki.
このスタンプ 外してもらえるか?
Can you take off this stamp?
I can't guarantee your safety if I take it off.
それを外しちゃったら もうここから先
あなたの安全は保障できないよ?
決闘って奴 してみたいんだ
I want to try this duel thing.
Did you take care of the formalities?
手続きっていうのは 済んだのかい?
Yes, of course.
ああ もちろん
そのあたり抜かりねーよ あの人は
She's very diligent about that.
She chased down the first oddity slayer and negotiated with him.
あのあと ちゃんと初代怪異殺しを追跡して
しっかり交渉している
セッティングした決闘の場所っていうのは
どこなんだ?
Where do we have this duel you set up for us?
僕は今夜 どこに行けばいい?
Where do I have to go?
あー それな
Oh, that.
You should be familiar with it.
お前にとっちゃあ馴染みのある場所だよ
俺にとっては因縁の場所って感じだが
I have some fateful attachments to it too.
因縁の?
Fateful?
私立直江津高校のグラウンドだ
The grounds of Naoetsu Private High School.
神原から あれだけの叱咤(しった)激励を受けた忍の
次なる行動は
Having been thoroughly reprimanded by Kanbaru,
拗(す)ねて寝る だった
Shinobu decided to pout and go to sleep.
彼女は 社の奥に引っ込んでしまった
She hid in the shrine.
子高生に論破されたことが
思いのほか応えたということだろう
Having been obliterated by a high
school girl must have gotten to her.
あれ? 神原 どうしたんだ?
Huh? What are you doing, Kanbaru?
そんなところで寝転がって
Why are you sleeping here?
頭から血が出てるぞ
You're bleeding on your head.
大丈夫なのか?
Are you okay?
阿良々木先輩 さっきまでそこで見てたんだから
知ってるだろ?
Weren't you hiding over there, Araragi?
You know the answer.
You knew?!
バレてたのかよ!
大丈夫
Don't worry.
忍ちゃんは気付いていなかった
Shinobu didn't notice.
で 阿良々木先輩
頼んだ本は買ってきてくれたか?
So, Araragi, did you buy me my books?
Is that really the most important thing right now?
頼んだ本にこだわり過ぎだ
頼んだ本 どれだけ重要なんだよ
How important are they to you?
せめて頭の傷を見せろ
At least let me look at your head.
まあ 大丈夫か
She'll be fine.
さあ 昼ごはん食べようぜ 神原
Let's have lunch, Kanbaru.
では 私はこのまま本を読んでるから
阿良々木先輩が食べさせてくれ
I'll just start reading now, so feed me.
あーんじゃねえよ
No way.
そこまで甘やかす先輩がいるわけないだろ
Who'd do that for their junior?
忍は?
Where's Shinobu?
で 阿良々木先輩 ブラは?
What about the bra, Araragi?
買って来てやったよ
I bought it.
Here.
Bra
ほら
I'll just start reading now, so put it on.
では 私はこのまま本を読んでるから
阿良々木先輩がつけてくれ
That's a totally different moan!
あーんの意味が変わっちゃってんじゃねえか
神原 ところで 僕にはないか?
Kanbaru, by the way.
身体を張ったアドバイスみたいなの
Do you have some death-defying advice for me too?
強いて言うならＤＩＹだ
I'd tell you DIY if you really want something.
ＤＩＹ?
DIY?
ドゥ・ユア・ベスト
Do Your Best.
Hang in there!
ベストを尽くせ
That would come out to DYB abbreviated.
それを略したらＤＹＢであって
Do-It-Yourselfer
ＤＩＹは日曜大工だと思ったが
DIY means Do It Yourself.
しかし そこは突っ込まないことにした
I decided against correcting her,
なぜなら ドゥ・イト・ユアセルフ "自分でやれ"と言うのは
今回の僕には まったく相応しいアドバイスだったからである
since it perfectly fit the current situation.
I hear your laughter beyond the door
You were supposed to be with me forever
I breathed onto the classroom window and wrote your name
only to panic and wipe it with my sleeve
I heard your voice from the hallway
and went home in hurry to hide my feelings
At some point I became unable
to talk to you normally
I can hear your laughter beyond the door
You were supposed to be next to me forever
You knew how I felt
even when I said nothing
Now I know how important you were to me,
but we will never see each other again